Hotel Variety is a action, music, crime film directed by Raymond Cannon.
A New York City boarding house for vaudeville
performers, none of whom have any steady work....
Grand Hotel is a 1932 American pre-Code drama film directed by
Edmund Goulding and produced by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer.
The screenplay by William A.
Drake is based on the 1930 play by Drake, who had adapted it from
the 1929 novel Menschen im Hotel by Vicki Baum.
MGM remade the film as Week-End at the Waldorf in 1945.
The  German remake Menschen im Hotel was released in 1959, and it served as the
basis for the 1989 Tony Award-winning stage musical Grand Hotel.
In 1977, MGM announced a musical remake, to take place at Las Vegas' MGM Grand Hotel
and directed by Norman Jewison, but the production was cancelled.
Grand Hotel has proven influential in the years since its release.
The iconic line "I want to be alone", famously delivered by Greta Garbo,
placed number 30 in AFI's 100 Years...100 Movie Quotes.
To date, it is the only film to have won the Academy Award for Best
Picture without being nominated in any other category.
In 2007, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress for being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".